Okay, hi, um as part of our sub 2
compliance audit we have to write a
software development like cycle document or an FDLC.
And this is my attempt at getting the ball rolling on that.
So I put it in this .github org here as a pull request.
.github is a convention used by GitHub where you
can store sort of org-wide configuration in there.
So I figured this might be a good place to keep some document about
how we use GitHub. Um so in this document I sort
of tried to straddle the line between writing a document that is catering
to the requirements and expectations of- the SOC 2
process, but also being a document that is hopefully actually
useful for new uh employees and contractors who are
joining the company and want to know how we do software development.
So it covers a lot, covers how we use GitHub,
covers our branching methodology,
how we should structure projects,
how to do documentation,
how to standardize on a sort of,
scripts for making projects approachable for new developers,
how to do PRs, how to do code review,
and basically the whole life cycle,
how we do releases, how we do deployment,
feature flags, etcetera.
And so a lot of it is GitHub specific, but there's also some content
in here about the various kind of external services that we use.
Um, there's a section in here about a depend about and how we use
that, which is Thank you. Uh,
one of the necessary parts of the stock two requirements.
Um, so this is ready for a look.
There are a few outstanding issues though and I'm not quite sure how to
proceed on them. So I took the contents of this current draft and
I'm paste it into Quad and ask if it's looking good enough.
Um, and it has some interesting feedback.
So uh,
the first one about access control, it says umm,
you need to describe how you regularly review and update access permissions.
So there's a section in the document I have here about our onboarding and
offboarding checklist. Um,
but one issue is that we have historically been very generous with permissions
when somebody joins the team even has a contractor.
We of just give them access to the entire organization.
Um, so something we might want to consider
here is do we need to implement a process for determining
who needs access to what and being more strict about it.
Um,
another thing is change management seems to be a very big
topic for this. Um,
SDLC thing. I haven't really broached the topic of,
How we plan and propose and approve the work
that we're going. Of course that's you know actively being
sort of refined or revised.
By our team, but I don't know how much I want to get into
that in this document. Um.
I know we're sort of using a combination of linear and GitHub
and notion and varying degrees and it's kind of up in the air.
So, um, I would love feedback on how to address that bit there.
Um.
Full durability management. I feel like this is actually pretty well covered.
I didn't cover back up in recovery because I don't actually really know much
about this. Um.
And then there's this section about vendor management and we could go into great
detail about all the the third party vendors we work with.
But I don't specifically know what our processes are for assessing
them. Whether they're making sure they're up to snap monitoring their
compliance etc.
So those are the outstanding things.
Umm.
Also happy to move this doc somewhere else if it makes more sense.
Might just make. A sense to put it in motion.
Umm. But since it is good.
So get hub specific. I thought this might be a good place to start.
Anyway, uhh looking forward to feedback and I hope this is useful.
Thanks. Bye.